REKHA N MADALLI

South Windsor, CT 06074 **Phone:** 603-852-6262 | **E-mail:** rnmadalli@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rekha-madalli-6b597119b/ https://github.com/rnm-code-repo?tab=repositories

Profile: https://rnm-code-repo.github.io/react-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Software developer with 2.5 years of experience in application development and testing with certificate in Full Stack Web Development. Resilient programmer, approaching challenges with multiple angles and team collaboration to optimize solutions. Strengths in meeting deadlines, team player and an avid learner. Positioned well to develop a unique perspective to responsive UI and backend components utilizing various JavaScript frameworks.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, PL/SQL, JavaScript, HTML, SQL, XML/XSLT

Web Technologies: NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, Webpacks, PWA

Tools/Process: GitHub, JIRA, VC Code, Eclipse, Agile, Waterfall, Kanban

Database: Oracle, MongoDB, ORM

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2004 - 2006

Wipro Technologies

Key person in developing UI components and data modules for UI.

Wrote technical documents by communicating with project stakeholders and clients to cover 100% requirements. Coordinating development and testing efforts to ensure quality of project.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Design and Development of UI Components
- Quality assurance of project deliverables
- Designed, developed, debugged and implemented UI components for web application
- Responsible for investigating the issues, defects, root-cause analysis, formulating corrective action and implementing them
- Creating SQL queries and test cases to validate data and provide input on corrective measures

Key Accomplishments:

- Quickly Promoted to a role with more responsibilities and was a key member of the project in delivering technical documents and quality assurance to ensure the worth of the project
- Integrated UI components with data objects. Conducted unit testing by developing test cases that helped in code optimization and reduce testing redundancies by 25%

Web Developer 2016 - Present

Hoysala Kannada Koota hkkct.org

Volunteering work at Non-profit organization

Community portal hkkct.org is the online portal for local Indian community. Members rely on this website to stay in touch with the other community members and also to register and participate in various community events.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Part of a team that designed and Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and User Experience, resulting in 40% increase in community participation.
- Integrated Google Analytics to get the statistics for the traffic to the website.
- Created custom HTML emails for Newsletters and invitations .
- Implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Successfully identified and diagnosed and fixed website problems including broken links, typographical errors and formatting issues.
- Responsible for Integrating PayPal payment gateway to the website.
- Creating web forms for participant registrations and reservation of the slots booking for various cultural activities for up to 300 participants.

Key Accomplishments:

• Key person in designing a webpage dedicated to information about Green Initiative which reduced the plastic usage among community members by 35%

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development - Boot Camp University of Connecticut Hartford, CT

2019 - 2020

A full stack web development program focused on MERN stack.

Worked on various projects that included full implementation of project from UI development to backend coding and deployment.

Key Accomplishments:

- Design, development of all components of application
- Deployment of application on Heroku and GitHub
- Team projects focused on achieving project goals in short time with Agile methodology

PROJECTS

My-Garage

https://github.com/smaji08/mygarage-kaera https://lit-scrubland-58683.herokuapp.com/mygarage-kaera

- Website that provides registered users to subscribe to vehicle maintenance service (onsite or in service stations)
- Responsible for design and development of APIs to search and store vehicles by VIN, landing page to display User profile. Development of Rest APIs to manage user data
- HTML, CSS, ReactJS, React-Bootstrap, web hooks for UI development, Express/Axios for Rest APIs, Mongo DB and ORM for data management

CookOut

https://github.com/smaji08/CookOut https://smaji08.github.io/CookOut/

- Website that allows user to search for gourmet locations within a specified radius of their current location and choose a place to order takeout, delivery, dine in or search for recipes
- Responsible for design and development of APIs to search and display recipe and details, landing page
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, web hooks for UI development, Express/Axios for Rest APIs

FinTrack

https://github.com/zvlu/FinTRack https://serene-scrubland-32480.herokuapp.com/

- Web application that allows users to track the Income and Expenses and allot desired portion of Income into Savings and Investment in Stock market
- Responsible for design, development of stock search page and functionality
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, CSS, Charts, Rest APIs to get stock data using Express/Axios, Mongo DB and ORM to store user data

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Connecticut, Hartford, CT

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, ORM, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Engineering: Kuvempu University, Karnataka, India

Engineering degree in Instrumentation Technology. Graduated with Honors.

OTHER INTERESTS

- Community activities Raising funds for food banks, homeless shelters and animal shelters through various non-profit organizations
- Treasurer of Non-Profit organization VSNA CT Chapter vsna.org